Guide to the Stanford Humanities Center, Harry Camp Memorial Lectures
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Stanford Humanities Center, Harry Camp Memorial Lectures
1963-2006
SC1070
Stanford University. Humanities Center.
1 Linear feet (3 boxes)
Audio and video recordings of lectures.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
The Harry Camp Memorial Fund was established in 1956 by friends and associates of Harry Camp. A prominent businessman and philanthropist in San Francisco, Camp was described as a "gentle and wise humanitarian." The fund brings outstanding speakers to the University for public lectures and promotes the study of "the concept of the dignity and the worth of the individual." The Camp Lectures are presented every other year.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes audio and video recordings of lectures. Included are Anthony Sampson's lecture "Mandela, Reconciliation and Shakespeare," 2002; Elaine Pagel's lectures on the Gospel of Thomas and politics and religion, 2004; and Anthony Grafton's lectures "The First Theorists of History" and "The Life and Death of a Genre," 2006.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged chronologically.
Access Terms
Geertz, Clifford.; Simon, Herbert Alexander, 1916-; Lectures.
Collection Contents
- Audiovisual Materials, Series 1
  - Simon, Herbert A., "Grappling With the Hard Problems: The Uses of Reason in Human Affairs", 1982 Feb; 1.1-1.5; 5 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Geertz, Clifford, "Works and Lives: The Anthropologist as Author", 1983 May; 1.6-1.9; 4 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Weiskrantz, Lawrence, "To Have But Not to Hold.", 1997 Oct 13; 2.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Weiskrantz, Lawrence, "Thought Without Language, Thought Without Awareness?", 1997 Oct 14; 2.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Weiskrantz, Lawrence, "The Blind Leading the Sighted, and Learning From their Pupils.", 1997 Oct 15; 2.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2.9)
  - Weiskrantz, Lawrence, "Imaging the Imageless.", 1997 October 16; 2.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Pagel, Elaine, "Revisioning Christianity: New Perspectives from the Gospel of Thomas", 2004 Jan 26; 2.2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Pagel, Elaine, "Politics and Religion: How and When Do They Begin to Separate?", 2004 Jan 28; 2.3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Grafton, Anthony, "What Was History? The Art of History in Early Modern Europe", 2006 Jan 30; 2.5; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2.5U)
  - Grafton, Anthony, "The First Theorists of History,", 2006 Jan 30; 3 computer file(s); 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2)
  - Grafton, Anthony, "The Life and Death of a Genre", 2006 Feb 1; 2.6; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 2)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 2.6U)
  - Sampson, Anthony, "Mandela, Reconciliation and Shakespeare", 2002 Jan 22; 2.1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
- Additional Materials, Series 2
  Materials in this series were previously classified in the Stanford University Publications and Ephemera Collection "4digit" collection.
  - Ephemera, 1963-1992 (Box 1)